<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>martinrosvall.com</title>
    <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com" />
    <updated>2021-06-04T10:25:24+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Martin Rosvall</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.martinrosvall.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Regularities in species niches reveal the world’s climatic regions</title>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rosvall</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com/human-activity-is-altering-the-worlds-zoogeographical-regions-3.html"/>
        <id>https://www.martinrosvall.com/human-activity-is-altering-the-worlds-zoogeographical-regions-3.html</id>
            <category term="Publications"/>

        <updated>2021-06-04T10:25:24+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/21/klimatzoner-pa-jorden-30430crop07120991181resize1280720autoorientquality90density150stripextensionjpgid16.jpg" alt="The distribution of vertebrate animals redefines temperate and cold climate regions" />
                    Joaquín Calatayud, Magnus Neuman, Alexis Rojas, Anton Eriksson, and Martin Rosvall Climate regions form the basis of many ecological,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/21/klimatzoner-pa-jorden-30430crop07120991181resize1280720autoorientquality90density150stripextensionjpgid16.jpg" alt="The distribution of vertebrate animals redefines temperate and cold climate regions" />
                <p><strong>Joaquín Calatayud</strong>, <strong>Magnus Neuman</strong>, <strong>Alexis Rojas</strong>, <strong>Anton Eriksson</strong>, and <strong>Martin Rosvall</strong></p>
<p>Climate regions form the basis of many ecological, evolutionary and conservation studies. However, our understanding of climate regions is limited to how they shape vegetation: They do not account for the distribution of animals. Here we develop a network-based framework to identify important climates worldwide based on regularities in realized niches of about 26,000 tetrapods. We show that high-energy climates, including deserts, tropical savannas, and steppes, are consistent across animal- and plant-derived classifications, indicating similar underlying climatic determinants. Conversely, temperate climates differ across all groups, suggesting that these climates allow for idiosyncratic adaptations. Finally, we show how the integration of niche classifications with geographical information enables the detection of climatic transition zones and the signal of geographic and historical processes. Our results identify the climates shaping the distribution of tetrapods and call for caution when using general climate classifications to study the ecology, evolution, or conservation of specific taxa.</p>
<p><a class="noline" href="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.58397">eLife 10:e58397 (2021)</a><br><a class="noline" href="https://doi.org/10.1101/851030">bioRxiv 851030</a><br><a href="https://www.umu.se/en/news/distribution-of-vertebrates-redefines-temperate-and-cold-climate-regions_10143748/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Popular summary</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A multiscale view of the Phanerozoic fossil record reveals the three major biotic transitions</title>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rosvall</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com/human-activity-is-altering-the-worlds-zoogeographical-regions-2.html"/>
        <id>https://www.martinrosvall.com/human-activity-is-altering-the-worlds-zoogeographical-regions-2.html</id>
            <category term="Publications"/>

        <updated>2021-06-04T10:23:58+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/20/marine-fauna-30807crop0019191079resize1280720autoorientquality90density150stripextensionjpgid16.jpg" alt="A multiscale view of the marine life" />
                    Alexis Rojas, Joaquín Calatayud, Michal Kowalewski, Magnus Neuman, and Martin Rosvall The hypothesis of the Great Evolutionary Faunas is&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/20/marine-fauna-30807crop0019191079resize1280720autoorientquality90density150stripextensionjpgid16.jpg" alt="A multiscale view of the marine life" />
                <p><strong>Alexis Rojas</strong>, <strong>Joaquín Calatayud</strong>, <strong>Michal Kowalewski</strong>,<strong> Magnus Neuman</strong>, and <strong>Martin Rosvall</strong></p>
<p>The hypothesis of the Great Evolutionary Faunas is a foundational concept of macroevolutionary research postulating that three global mega-assemblages have dominated Phanerozoic oceans following abrupt biotic transitions. Empirical estimates of this large-scale pattern depend on several methodological decisions and are based on approaches unable to capture multiscale dynamics of the underlying Earth-Life System. Combining a multilayer network representation of fossil data with a multilevel clustering that eliminates the subjectivity inherent to distance-based approaches, we demonstrate that Phanerozoic oceans sequentially harbored four global benthic mega-assemblages. Shifts in dominance patterns among these global marine mega-assemblages were abrupt (end-Cambrian 494 Ma; end-Permian 252 Ma) or protracted (mid-Cretaceous 129 Ma), and represent the three major biotic transitions in Earth’s history. Our findings suggest that gradual ecological changes associated with the Mesozoic Marine Revolution triggered a protracted biotic transition comparable in magnitude to the end-Permian transition initiated by the most severe biotic crisis of the past 500 million years. Overall, our study supports the notion that both long-term ecological changes and major geological events have played crucial roles in shaping the mega-assemblages that dominated Phanerozoic oceans.</p>
<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s42003-021-01805-y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Communications Biology 4, 309 (2021)</a><br><a href="https://doi.org/10.1101/866186">bioRxiv 866186</a><br><a href="https://www.umu.se/en/news/gradual-changes-triggered-historical-shift-in-marine-fauna-_10216287/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Popular summary</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Maps of networks</title>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rosvall</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com/maps-of-networks.html"/>
        <id>https://www.martinrosvall.com/maps-of-networks.html</id>
            <category term="Interests"/>

        <updated>2020-02-27T09:28:05+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/16/schematic-mapgenerator.svg" alt="" />
                    On mapequation.org, we make Infomap and other applications based on the map equation available. For example, you can: Simplify and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/16/schematic-mapgenerator.svg" alt="" />
                <p>On <a href="https://www.mapequation.org/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mapequation.org</a>, we make Infomap and other applications based on the map equation available. For example, you can: </p>
<ul style="list-style-type: circle;">
<li>Simplify and highlight important structures in complex networks</li>
<li>Reveal structural change in complex networks</li>
<li>Identify biogeographical regions with Infomap Bioregions</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Duty above all?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rosvall</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com/duty-above-all.html"/>
        <id>https://www.martinrosvall.com/duty-above-all.html</id>
            <category term="Blog post"/>

        <updated>2019-11-04T15:39:31+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/8/plikten.png" alt="Duty above all" />
                     So, you are on your way home? When I was at your age, I never went home until&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/8/plikten.png" alt="Duty above all" />
                <blockquote>
<p>So, you are on your way home? When I was at your age, I never went home until eight o'clock!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It was only five o'clock when the white-haired professor lectured us in the elevator heading down to the entrance floor of the building at the University of Washington where I did my postdoc. Since then, countless researchers at various universities have answered my opening line, "How are you doing?" with the contagious, "There's too much going on now," before continuing with the jargon that long stressful work days are the only way forward.<br><br>Are never-ending work days the cost of freedom at work? Is it even beneficial for the research?<br><br>Indeed, it is possible to accomplish miracles during long stressful days at work, but many times, "There's too much going on now," is more about self-fraud in the absence of miracles. Once upon a time, long days were the means to achieve great accomplishments, but suddenly long days and stress became goals in themselves. It is so much easier to succeed in that way: Everyone can rise to the status of hero by dragging around in the bog of stress.<br><br>In elite sports, it is called overtraining and gives no status, because everyone knows that overtraining prevents results. With measurable goals it becomes apparent. The training culture that only counts hours does not breed stars. And as little as more miles will pay off for the training addict, will late evenings after already long days at work automatically lead to more research breakthroughs. The perceived security from doing more of the same is a red herring.<br><br>Of course, the solution is the cliché of balance and variation. Rationally, we know that training breaks down and recovery rebuilds, that long workouts must be followed by short workouts, hard workouts by easy, and that rest days are supercompensation days. But when the duty calls from oneself, colleagues, and funding agencies, it feels good to do a couple of extra hours despite muddy thoughts. "Everybody else does it." With duty before all, the collective march continues with heavy steps – at worst in circles.<br><br>The real challenge is to have the courage to break habits and inspire change. The hard thing comes first – to change oneself. It is hardly possible without actionable goals toward the answers to what we truly want to achieve. After that, everything is about never looking away from the goal and about inspiring others to joyful work toward new heights. There are many techniques to get there. Speaking for myself, I try to run with relaxed form and look naturally ahead to avoid cramping and maintain focus.<br>Moreover, there is nothing that beats power naps to keep the stress away and the thoughts clear. And if you ask how I am doing, then I hope I will use <a href="http://www.umu.se/sok/personalkatalog?languageId=3&amp;uid=fral0001">Fredrik Almqvist</a>'s reply: "Pretty darn well!" It is also contagious.</p>
<p><em>Originally published in Swedish as Plikten framför allt? for <a href="https://www.tidningencurie.se/gastbloggar/martinrosvall/plikten-framfor-allt/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Curie</a>, issued by the Swedish Research Council.</em></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Human activity is altering the world’s zoogeographical regions</title>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rosvall</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com/human-activity-is-altering-the-worlds-zoogeographical-regions.html"/>
        <id>https://www.martinrosvall.com/human-activity-is-altering-the-worlds-zoogeographical-regions.html</id>
            <category term="Publications"/>

        <updated>2020-02-27T07:05:43+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/12/BiogeographicalRobusness.jpg" alt="" />
                    Rubén Bernardo-Madrid, Joaquín Calatayud, Manuela González-Suarez, Martin Rosvall, Pablo M. Lucas, Marta Rueda, Alexandre Antonelli, and Eloy Revilla Zoogeographical&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/12/BiogeographicalRobusness.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><strong>Rubén Bernardo-Madrid,</strong> <strong>Joaquín Calatayud</strong>, <strong>Manuela González-Suarez</strong>, <strong>Martin Rosvall</strong>, <strong>Pablo M. Lucas</strong>, <strong>Marta Rueda</strong>, <strong>Alexandre Antonelli</strong>, and <strong>Eloy Revilla</strong></p>
<p>Zoogeographical regions, or zooregions, are areas of the Earth defined by species pools that reflect ecological, historical and evolutionary processes acting over millions of years. Consequently, researchers have assumed that zooregions are robust and unlikely to change on a human timescale. However, the increasing number of human‐mediated introductions and extinctions can challenge this assumption. By delineating zooregions with a network‐based algorithm, here we show that introductions and extinctions are altering the zooregions we know today. Introductions are homogenising the Eurasian and African mammal zooregions and also triggering less intuitive effects in birds and amphibians, such as dividing and redefining zooregions representing the Old and New World. Furthermore, these Old and New World amphibian zooregions are no longer detected when considering introductions plus extinctions of the most threatened species. Our findings highlight the profound and far‐reaching impact of human activity and call for identifying and protecting the uniqueness of biotic assemblages.</p>
<p><a class="noline" href="https://doi.org/10.1111/ele.13321">Ecology Letters <strong>22</strong>, 1297–1305 (2019)</a> <br><a class="noline" href="https://doi.org/10.1101/287300">bioRxiv 287300</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Understanding Complex Systems: From Networks to Optimal Higher-Order Models</title>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rosvall</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com/understanding-complex-systems-from-networks-to-optimal-higher-order-models.html"/>
        <id>https://www.martinrosvall.com/understanding-complex-systems-from-networks-to-optimal-higher-order-models.html</id>
            <category term="Publications"/>
            <category term="Higher-order network models"/>

        <updated>2020-02-27T07:06:56+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/1/HigherOrderNetworkModels-04.svg" alt="Higher-order Markov flows" />
                    Renaud Lambiotte, Martin Rosvall, and Ingo Scholtes Rich data are revealing that complex dependencies between the nodes of a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/1/HigherOrderNetworkModels-04.svg" alt="Higher-order Markov flows" />
                <p><strong>Renaud Lambiotte</strong>, <strong>Martin Rosvall</strong>, and <strong>Ingo Scholtes</strong></p>
<p>Rich data are revealing that complex dependencies between the nodes of a network may not be captured by models based on pairwise interactions. Higher-order network models go beyond these limitations, offering new perspectives for understanding complex systems.</p>
<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41567-019-0459-y" title="Paper" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nature Physics <strong>15</strong>, 313–320 (2019)</a><br><a class="noline" href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1806.05977">arXiv:1806.05977</a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Helping businesses love their data</title>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rosvall</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com/infobaleen.html"/>
        <id>https://www.martinrosvall.com/infobaleen.html</id>
            <category term="Interests"/>

        <updated>2019-11-26T06:37:52+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/17/InfobaleenNKlogo_Purple.svg" alt="Infobaleen" />
                    I am co-founder of Infobaleen together with Daniel Edler, Andrea Lancichinetti, Niklas Lovén, Christian Persson, and Jakob Sjölander. Infobaleen&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/17/InfobaleenNKlogo_Purple.svg" alt="Infobaleen" />
                I am co-founder of <a href="http://infobaleen.com/">Infobaleen</a> together with <a href="https://www.umu.se/en/staff/daniel-edler/">Daniel Edler</a>, <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/andrealancichinetti/">Andrea Lancichinetti</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/niklasloven">Niklas Lovén</a>, <a href="https://se.linkedin.com/in/christian-persson-025ba153">Christian Persson</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jakob-sj%C3%B6lander-7821642">Jakob Sjölander</a>. Infobaleen is a university spin-off that combines efficient machine learning and data management in a scalable platform. We make our customers' data work for them.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>My journey in life and science</title>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rosvall</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com/bio.html"/>
        <id>https://www.martinrosvall.com/bio.html</id>
            <category term="Interests"/>

        <updated>2021-05-31T20:16:59+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/11/MartinRosvallBlogg.jpg" alt="Skiing with kids" />
                    My life is an improv dance with family, cross-country skiing, outdoor fun, and research. I was born in Uppsala&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/11/MartinRosvallBlogg.jpg" alt="Skiing with kids" />
                <p><em>My life is an improv dance with family, cross-country skiing, outdoor fun, and research. </em></p>
<p>I was born in Uppsala and grew up in a small village north of Umeå. At 16, I went to a high school for cross-country skiing in Lycksele before my undergraduate in engineering physics. After my Ph.D. in network science at the Niels Bohr Institute in Copenhagen, I moved to the Department of Biology at the University of Washington in Seattle for my postdoc. There I started working on a grand challenge in network science: how to simplify and highlight essential regularities in networks into maps. Mapping networks is a holy grail of data science because in the myriad links and nodes of a network hide answers to how we can predict how the system will evolve.</p>
<p>From 2009 at Umeå University, and since 2019 as a professor in physics with focus on computational science, I have continued to develop and integrate new math, algorithms, and visualizations into mapping tools for efficiently going from interaction data to insightful maps, new hypotheses, and unexpected discoveries. With a diverse research group in <a href="https://icelab.se" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IceLab</a> and a growing collaboration network, our applications extend across both the natural and social sciences.</p>
<p>As a professional power napper, my favorite place in IceLab after lunch is a hidden couch.</p>
<p>I am fortunate to live between the university and the ski trails with my wife Marie and our two daughters born in 2014 and 2018. When I am not in a playground with my daughters, you will find me increasing my dopamine levels on cross-country skis.</p>
<p>Currently, my research is funded by the Swedish Research Council, the Swedish Foundation for Strategic Research, the Knut and Alice Wallenberg Foundation, and the Kempe Foundation.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In May 2021, <a href="https://sunelehmann.com">Sune Lehmann</a> interviewed me in his podcast <a href="https://sunelehmann.com/2021/03/23/podcast-trailer-too-lazy-to-read-the-paper/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Too Lazy to Read the Paper</a> about how I became a network scientist.</p>
<figure class="post__video"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="314" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GaxnC8MtUW4" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Oh, well. What&#x27;s an interdisciplinary workshop?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rosvall</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com/oh-well-whats-an-interdisciplinary-workshop.html"/>
        <id>https://www.martinrosvall.com/oh-well-whats-an-interdisciplinary-workshop.html</id>

        <updated>2019-11-15T08:49:12+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/18/IceLabCamp-1.jpg" alt="" />
                    As a young disoriented PhD student, I was invited to an interdisciplinary workshop in the outskirts of the Fontainebleau&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/18/IceLabCamp-1.jpg" alt="" />
                As a young disoriented PhD student, I was invited to an interdisciplinary workshop in the outskirts of the Fontainebleau forest south of Paris. It became a defining moment for me as a researcher. I came there as a student who knew how to answer questions, following well-established recipes. After a week with French Master's students from different disciplines, doing nothing but asking questions and juggling ideas, I left as an explorer into the unknown guided by research questions.<br><br>While I have been lost many times also after the workshop, I never lost the inner compass and the excitement for the unknown. Instead I decided that one day, when I have support to organize a similar workshop, I will pay back to the scientific community and organize a similar workshop. Today I am coming back from my seventh, hoping that some of the more than one hundred Master's students, PhD students, and Postdocs who have participated over the years still can fuel themselves with memories from the many magical aha! moments I have witnessed. <br><br><a href="https://icelab.se/event/icelab-camp-2019/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IceLab Camp</a> is about all that coffee break wisdom that it can take years to collect. Equipped only with their curiosity and creativity, the participants let ideas meet and mate to carve out interdisciplinary research proposals. It is a four day long tour de force into the unknown, accompanied by the beauty that autumn days in Northern Sweden can offer, to achieve researcher's high.<br>
<blockquote>Oh, well. What's an interdisciplinary workshop? After all, I suppose it would be frightfully dull, and-and-and boring, and-and completely... Completely wonderful.</blockquote>
<em>In the Professor Magenta podcast episode <a href="https://soundcloud.com/professormagenta/research-remix-cut" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PM SPECIAL – Är framtidens forskning den gränslösa</a> (10 minutes), one of the participants, Katarina Bendtz from Stockholm University, interviews three other participants from the workshop. Akbar Espaillat, Mariana Mariana Buongermino Pereira, and Ulf Aslak Jensen give a brief introduction to their PhD projects and explain how their research combines methods from different disciplines in a productive way. The students are affiliated with MIMS, Umeå University, Chalmers University of Technology and Copenhagen University, respectively.</em>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Mapping change in large networks</title>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rosvall</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.martinrosvall.com/mapping-change-in-large-networks.html"/>
        <id>https://www.martinrosvall.com/mapping-change-in-large-networks.html</id>
            <category term="Selected publications"/>
            <category term="Publications"/>

        <updated>2020-03-03T21:50:07+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/15/neuroAlluvial2001-2007.svg" alt="" />
                    Martin Rosvall and Carl T. Bergstrom Change is a fundamental ingredient of interaction patterns in biology, technology, the economy, and science&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.martinrosvall.com/media/posts/15/neuroAlluvial2001-2007.svg" alt="" />
                <p><strong>Martin Rosvall</strong> and <strong>Carl T. Bergstrom</strong></p>
<p>Change is a fundamental ingredient of interaction patterns in biology, technology, the economy, and science itself: Interactions within and between organisms change; transportation patterns by air, land, and sea all change; the global financial flow changes; and the frontiers of scientific research change. Networks and clustering methods have become important tools to comprehend instances of these large-scale structures, but without methods to distinguish between real trends and noisy data, these approaches are not useful for studying how networks change. Only if we can assign significance to the partitioning of single networks can we distinguish meaningful structural changes from random fluctuations. Here we show that bootstrap resampling accompanied by significance clustering provides a solution to this problem. To connect changing structures with the changing function of networks, we highlight and summarize the significant structural changes with alluvial diagrams and realize de Solla Price's vision of mapping change in science: studying the citation pattern between about 7000 scientific journals over the past decade, we find that neuroscience has transformed from an interdisciplinary specialty to a mature and stand-alone discipline.</p>
<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0008694">PLoS One 5(1): e8694 (2010)</a><br><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/0812.1242">arXiv:0812.1242</a></p>
<p>Code for the community-detection algorithm <a href="https://www.mapequation.org/code.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Infomap</a>, <a href="https://www.mapequation.org/infomap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Infomap online</a>, and <a href="https://www.mapequation.org/apps.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">interactive applications</a> for <a href="https://www.mapequation.org/apps/MapGenerator.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">generating network maps</a>, <a href="https://www.mapequation.org/navigator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">exploring networks</a>, <a href="https://www.mapequation.org/alluvial/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">visualizing changes in networks</a> and explaining the machinery of  the map equation for <a href="https://www.mapequation.org/apps/MapDemo.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">standard</a>, <a href="https://www.mapequation.org/apps/multilayer-network/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">multilevel</a>, and <a href="https://www.mapequation.org/apps/sparse-memory-network/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">higher-order</a> networks are available on <a href="https://www.mapequation.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mapequation.org</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
